

Jafar Shodiq

Data Enthusiast

East Jakarta, Indonesia +6281382378203 j.shodiq2312@gmail.com



Technical Skills

Data cleaning
Data analysis
Data visualization
Data modeling
Database development

Hobbies

Running and working out
Learning new languages
Competing in sports/games

Profile

Passionate data enthusiast with a handful experience working with structured and unstructured data. Creative thinker and adept at scraping, analyzing, cleaning, visualizing, and testing valuable data while communicating the needs for projects. Equipped with Python, R, and SQL, strives to get the most out of the available data. Resourceful and committed to continually advancing my knowledge of relevant technologies. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

Experience –

Data Scientist (Internship) at PT. Telkom Indonesia

July 2021 - Present

Have been working with customer data who are experiencing slow internet connection

Artificial Intelligence Developer (Internship) at PT. Telkom Indonesia

March 2021 - June 2021

- Worked with unstructured data and developed image processing model while also helping with audio processing development.
- Transformed the developed projects into API

Self-Study

August 2020 - Present

Have been taking online courses and working on various projects.

Android Developer

January 2019 – February 2019

Built a monitoring app on Android in a team of 4.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Engineering, Diponegoro University, Semarang

2016 - 2020

■ GPA: 3.69

Undergraduate thesis topic: deep learning

Non-Formal Courses

2020 - Present

Python, R, Scala, SQL, CLI, Spark, Statistics and Probability, Data Cleaning, Data Visualization, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, Time Series, Big Data.

Volunteer Experience

Coordinator of Volunteers for KKN

2020

- Led a small volunteer group of 5 people in Cangkring, Demak, Central Java for a total of 3 months.
- Surveyed and documented what potential Cangkring holds.
- Communicated and cooperated with the locals.
- Oversaw the group to make sure the tasks are properly done.

Member and Head Division at Computer Engineering Research Club

2017 - 2019

- Participated in routine club meeting and game-making project.
- Responsible for Audio division and led a group of 6 people.
- Presented in front of the club about how to use FL Studio (an audio making tool).
- Made a how-to module about the above presentation.

Assistant Professor at Diponegoro University, Semarang

2017 - 2019

- Teaching assistant of up to 80 students on Basic Computer and Programming subject.
- Oversaw class of up to 20 students on Artificial Neural Network subject.
- Documented attendance and completed assignments to maintain full class and student records.
- Assisted with clerical tasks such as copying papers, collecting assignments, and preparing materials for upcoming classes.

Staff of Talent Acquisition at AIESEC

2016 - 2017

- Expanded my network with new interesting people.
- Designed some posters to advertise the organization's projects.
- Helped with interviewing new volunteers who applied to the projects.